我有一子]_者了
It's been a while since I was
我想我只好照著提~卡念吧
...up here in front of you maybe i'll stick to the cards
髀我涉及公路和屋l生的事
There's been speculation that I was involved in the events that occurred on the freeway and the rooftop.
抱歉，你真的以槲相信
I'm sorry, Mr. Stark, but do you honestly expect us to believe that
一名穿著F盔甲的保S好出F
that was  bodyguard in a suit
r且你平常很ПｇS
that conveniently appeared,despite the fact that you historically despise bodyguards?
Yes.
而且@名神秘保S居然配有…
And this mysterious bodyguard was...
斯塔克工I最先M的高C密武器
...somehow equipped with...
莫斯科
...an undisclosed Stark high-tech powered battle suit?
我知道@令人y以理解
I know that it's confusing.
但|疑官方f法是一回事
It is one thing to question the official story
瞎猜我是超英雄…
and another thing entirely to make wild accusations
又是另一回事
or insinuate that I'm a superhero.
老f，我不是英雄的料
I mean, let's face it I'm not,the heroic type.
我的人格有很多缺陷
I've a laundry list of character defects,all the mistakes that I've made...
而且也公_做^S多蠢事
largely public.
事是…
The truth is...
我就是Fb
...I am Iron Man.
伊凡…
Ivan ...
伊凡?
Ivan?
那是你
That should be you.
e他胡f八道
Do not listen to these morons.
Σ黄
I'm sorry.
我只能o你我的知R
I can only offer you my knowledge.
“斯塔克工I”
“方舟反t”
“安|?f科 霍A德?斯塔克”
“托尼是Fb”
“斯塔克的方舟反t”
“托尼?斯塔克：我是Fb”
“r代sI年度L人物”
“Fb定|西PS”
Iron Man stabilizes East-West relations
F b 2
L速30e，高度1f5千尺
7-0 at 30 knots.Holding steady at 15000 feet.
你F在可以M入降落^
You are clear for exfiltration over the drop zone.
6月後
Six months later
斯塔克博[ ~s法拉盛
回碚婧茫
It's good to be back!
你很想我
You missed me.
炸掉什N吧！
Blow something up!
炸掉什N？我诌^了呀！
Blow something up?I already did that.
我]有f多年砣球K於S持…
I'm not saying that the world is enjoying...
L期的和平B是因槲
...its longest period of uninterrupted peace in years...because of me.
我也]f世上]人像我一
I'm not saying...that from the ashes of captivity...
如同浴火P凰般重@新生
...never has a greater Phoenix metaphor been personified in human history.
我更]f美政府能好整以暇
I'm not saying...that Uncle Sam can kick back on a lawn chair,...sipping on iced tea,...
因槲沂冀K保持p峰B
...because I haven't come across anyone who's man enough...
]人敢跟我翁簦
...to go toe to toe with me on my best day!
我勰悖Fb！
I love you Tony!
拜，我不重要
Please. It's not about me.
你也不重要
It's not about you.
我都不重要，重要的是鞒
It's not even about us.It's about legacy.
我替未硎来留下什N
It's about what we choose to leave behind for future generations.
所以拿髂觊_始
And that's why for the next year...
自1974年以淼牡谝淮
and for the first time since 1974,...
碜匀世界不同家和公司…
...the best and brightest men and women
最秀的人才⑻峁┧的Y源
...of nations and corporations the world over...
分享他的共同h
will pool their resources share their collective vision,
造一更美好的未
to leave behind a brighter future.
我K不重要
It's not about us!
我想f的是…
Therefore, what I am saying,if I'm saying anything,
g迎⒂^斯塔克工I博[
...is welcome back to the Stark Expo!
有位特e嘉e那笆阑
Now, making a special guest appearance from the great beyond,
向你f明@一切
to tell you what it's all about,
g迎我父H，霍A德
please welcome my father, Howard.
科技能_成一切
Everything is achievable through technology.
更美好的生活、更健康的身w
Better living.Robust health.
@是人v史上第一次…
And for the first time in human history,
能_成世界和平的可能
the possibility of world peace.
我代表斯塔克工I
So from all of us here at Stark Industries,I would like to personally introduce you to
向各位介B未淼某鞘
The city of the future.
科技人充Mo限的可能
technology holds infinite possibilities for mankind.
“血液毒性：19%”
Blood toxicity 19%
科技⒑芸旄淖你的日常生活
soon, technology will affect the way you live your life every day.
不必再辛苦工作
No more tedious work,
空出rgM行休f活
leaving more time,leisure activities
K且享受美好生活
and enjoying sweet life.
g迎⒂^斯塔克工I博[
The Stark Expo.Welcome.
者在斯塔克工I博[B
We are coming to you live from the kick-off of the Stark Expo
托尼?斯塔克走下舞_
where Tony Stark has just walked onstage.
各位今晚不能]PS
Don't worry if you can't make it down here now,
因椴┯[⒊掷me行一整年
because this expo goes on all year long.
我⒂^碜允澜绺鞯
And I'm gonna be here checking out all the attractions
不同的O施、位和l明
and the pavillions and the inventions from all around the world.
外面一片混y，小心c
It's a zoo out there, watch out alright.
_T，我走吧
Open up. Let's go.
大家好，x了，我得你
Nice to see you, alright.Thank you.I remember you.
打o我
Call me.
蛄
Hey, come on ...
你好
Hi there,
你能臀液名幔
dear friend.
我的s幸
It'll be a pleasure.
再了，小鬼
See ya buddy.
@是瑞
This is Larry.
甲骨文的k人，幸了
The oracle of goracle.What a pleasure, nice to see you.
再打o我
Call me.
瑞?金   瑞！
- Larry King.- Larry!
棒呆了，我的粉z
Yes, my people, my people.
K於出砹
Come on, Tony. There we go.
他算很冷o嘛
Very mellow.
不算太糟
It wasn't so bad.
完美O了
it's perfect.
你看，全新款
Look what we got here,the new model.
她是S附的幔   希望是喔
- Hey, does she come with the car?- I certainly hope so.
你是l？
Hi. And you are?
谭ü   m妞，我喜g
- Marshall. - Irish. I like it.
幸了，托尼
Pleased to meet you Tony
我黹_，行幔
I'm on the wheel, you mind?
你打哪淼模   德福
- Where you from?- Bedford.
你磉@e致铮   我碚夷
- What are you doing here?- Looking for you.
告V我…
Yeah? You found me.
你找我致铮
What are you up to later?
f髌苯o你
Serving subpoenas.
Yikes.
他不喜ge人o他|西
He doesn't like to be handed things.
@是我的怪癖
Yeah I have a peeve.
拿o我
I got it.
你被勒令在明早九c整
You are hereby ordered to appear before the Senate Armed Services Committee
出席⒆h院事委T
tomorrow morning at 9 am.
我能看你的警徽幔   他要看警徽
- Can I see a badge? - You wanna see the badge?
他特e喜g警徽
He likes the badge.
你是喜g幔
- You still like it?- Yup.
我xA府有多h？ A府？
- How far are we from D.C.?- D.C.?
250英里
250 miles.
A府
斯塔克先生，我^m才的h}
Mr. Stark, can we pick up now where we left off?
斯塔克先生！拜！
Mr. Stark?
是的，H鄣模
- Please.- Yes, dear?
你Ｐ穆我的
Can I have your attention?
]}
Absolutely.
你是否碛幸环N特殊武器？
Do you or do you not possess a specialized weapon?
]有
I do not.
你]有
You do not?
]e
I do not,
@要看你J槭颤N才算武器
well it depends how you define the word weapon.
Fb就算武器
The Iron Man weapon.
我的l明K不算武器
My device does not fit that description.
那你怎N形容它？
Well, how would you describe your..?
它是什N就是什N，⒆hT
I would describe it by defining it as what it is, sir.
它是什N？
As?
它是一N高科技的x肢
It's a high-tech prosthesis.
@是我想得到最好的形容~
That is, that's actually the most apt description I could make of it.
它是一N武器，它是武器
It's a weapon Mr Stark I hate to inform you it's a weapon.
如果你是以人民福祉先…
Please, if your priority was actually the well-being...
不，我是以把Fb@武器
My priority is to get the Iron Man weapon
交o美人民先
turned over to the people of the United States of America.
想都e想
Well, you can forget it.
我就是Fb
I am Iron Man.
我和F盔甲合橐惑w
The suit and I are one.
交出Fb就是交出我自己
To turn over the Iron Man suit would be to turn over myself, which is tantamount to
那算是谝刍蚴琴u淫…
indentured servitude or prostitution
要看你是在哪一州
depending on what state you're in.
我不能o你
I can't have it.
好，我不是＜
Look, I am no expert.
你然不是u淫＜
In prostitution? Of course not,
拜，你是⒆hT耶
you're a senator, come on!
我K不是武器＜
I'm not an expert in weapons.
但是我硪晃晃淦＜
But we have somebody here who is an expert on weapons.
我要举Z斯汀?h默
I would now like to call Justin Hammer
防部目前主要的火商
Our current primary weapons contractor.
我看h默先生走M
Let the record reflect that I observe Mr. Hammer entering the chamber
但我K]看任何武器＜
and I am wondering...if and when any actual expert will also be in attendance.
]e，我K不是＜
Absolutely. I am no expert.
你才是，托尼
I defer to you, Anthony.
你才是天才
You're the wonder boy.
⒆hT，容我l言
Senator, if I may...
或S我K不是＜
I may well not be an expert,
但你知道l才是真的＜遥
but you know who was the expert?
你父H！
Your dad!
霍A德?斯塔克
Howard Stark.
他不但是我的大家L
Really a father to us all.
更是事工I之父
and to the millitary-industrial age.
但是搞清楚，他不是嬉皮士
Let's just be clear, he was no flower child.
他是只雄He was a lion.
我都知道槭颤N磉@e
We all know why we are here:
@半年
In the last six months,
托尼?斯塔克打造了一把犀利
Anthony Stark has created a sword with untold possibilities.
他s猿帜侵皇且幻娑芘
And yet I insists it's a shield.
它要我信任他
He asks us to trust him
要我躲在他後面
as we cower behind it.
我真希望我X得很安全
I wish I were comforted, Anthony.
我是真的@N希望
I really do.
我很希望出Tr不必iT
I'd like to leave my door unlocked when I leave the house,
但@e不是加拿大
but this ain't Canada.
我活在充M危U的世界
You know we live in a world of grave threats,
斯塔克先生不一定能A知的危U
threats that Mr. Stark will not always be able to foresee.
xx各位
Thank you. God bless
天佑Fb，天佑美
Iron Man, God bless America.
f得好，h默先生
Well said, Mr. Hammer.
F在我要邀…
The committee would now like to invite
詹姆斯?_德中校出席h
Lieut. Col. James Rhodes to the chamber.
小_？
Rhodey?
兄弟，]想到你
Hey, buddy. Didn't expect to see you here.
是我，我砹耍接受事
Look, it's me. I'm here. Deal with it.
^m吧
Let's move on.
我只是…   ef了
- I just ...- Drop it. - Alright, I'll drop it.
@是_德中校收集到…
I have before me a complete report on the Iron Man weapon
有PFb武器的完整蟾
compiled by Colonel Rhodes.
中校，你念57第4段
and Colonel, for the record,can you please read page 57, paragraph 4?
你要我念蟾嬷械奶囟ǘ温洌
You're requesting that I read specific selections from my report, senator?
是的
Yes, sir.
我以槲沂碜觥
My understanding that I was going to be
完整及的蟾
testifying in a much more comprehensive and detailed manner.
我t解，但是今天有很多
I understand, a lot of things have changed today.
光是念出那一段落
You do understand that reading a single paragraph out of context
不能代表我的完整蟾
does not reflect the summary of my finding?
你念出恚中校
Just read it, Colonel. I do.
xx你
Thank you.
好吧
Very well.
FbK不`僬府任何挝
As he does not operate within any definable branch of government,
因此家安全及利益造成威The Iron Man presents a potential threat to the security of both the nation and to her interests.
但是我的Y是…
I did, however, go on to summarize that the benefits of
Fb的好h比奶更多
Iron Man far outweigh the liabilities
蛄
That's enough, Colonel.
斯塔克先生加入事指]w系
and that it would be in our interest
γ政府有利
to fold Mr Stark into the existing chain of command.
我不喜g加入任何w系
I'm not a joiner but
但我倒是可以考]防部L
I'll consider Secretary of Defense, if you ask nice.
工作r悼梢栽偕僖稽c
We can amend the hours a little bit.
我想播放你蟾嬷械挠跋
I'd like to go on and show, if I may,the imagery that's connected to your report.
我J槟壳斑不是…
I believe it is somewhat premature to reveal
向大公_@些影像的r候
these images to the general public at this time.
我能理解，中校
With all due respect, Colonel, I understand.
但如果你能形容@些影像
And if you could just narrate those for us,
我非常感激
we'd be very grateful.
把影像Show the images.
情Y@示@些影像中的b置
Intelligence suggests that the devices seen in these photos
其是斯塔克先生F盔甲的仿冒品
are in fact attempts at making manned copies of Mr. Stark's suit.
@一c^我的盟
This has been corroborated by our allies
以及地面情挝坏淖C
and local intelligence on the ground
@些F盔甲目前很可能可以使用
indicating that these suits are quite possibly at this moment operational.
等一下，o我看看
Hold on a second buddy, let me see.
有|西了，我真害
There's something here.Oh, boy I'm good.
我掌控了你的幕
Now can I get more screens.
我需要它
I need them.
@一切透明化了
Time for a little transparency.
我看看@到底是怎N回事
Let's see what's really going on.
他在做什N？
What is he doing?
你看X幕
If you'll direct your attention to said screens,
我相信那是北n
I believe that's North Korea.
能不能P掉？快P掉
Can you turn that off? Take it off.
伊朗
Iran.
]有o急乐氐耐No grave, immediate threat here.
那是Z斯汀?h默幔
Is that Justin Hammer?
他怎N也在搞仿冒品？   插^呢？
How did Hammer get in here?
Z斯汀，你上了
Justin, you're on TV, focus up.
很好，向右D
Left's good. Turn to the right.
糟了，糟了！
Oh, shit. Oh, shit!
大部份的家得花5到10年
Wow. Yeah, I'd say most countries, 5-10 years away.
h默工I至少要花20年
Hammer Industries 20.
容我指出那位I'd like to point out that that test pilot survived.
我想我看蛄
I think we got the point that he's making.
他C明了他的看法
I don't think there's any reason...
我猜我只能f：不客
The point is you're welcome, I guess.
什N意思？
For what?
我能防止核鸬亩
Because, I'm your nuclear deterrent.
Fb很有用
It's working.
我很安全，美很安全
We're safe.America is secure.
你要我的a品？想都e想！
You want my property?You can't have it!
不^我土四大忙
But did I you a big favor.
我一人就能S持世界和平
I've successfully privatized world peace.
你想要我怎樱
What more do you want?
F在就是@樱
For now!
我著和那些跳判〕蠛献
I'm tired of all of these ass clowns!
去你的，斯塔克先生
Fuck you Mr Stark.Fuck you buddy.
散，今天散
We're adjourned, we're adjourned for today.
好吧
Okay
你真是_心果
You've been a delight.
好，我全是榱巳嗣
My bond is with the people.
我樽约旱啡家服
And I will serve this great nation at the pleasure of myself.
如果我向全世界C明了什N
One thing I've proven
那就是你^δ苄刨我…
is that you can count on me ...
能自己很高d
...to pleasure myself.
加州R里布
醒醒吧，老爹回砹
Wake up, daddy's home.
g迎回家
Welcome home, sir.
恭喜博[_幕x式
Congratulations on the opening ceremonies.They were such a success.
以及⒆h院C大大地成功
as was your Senate hearing.
容我f一句
And may I say
你穿著衣服上令人耳目一新
how refreshing it is to finally see you in a video with your clothing on, sir?
你！
You!
我l誓我把你拆掉做成酒架
I swear to god I'll dismantle you, I'll switch your motherboard and turn you into wine rack.
@N臭|西我要喝多少？
How many ounces a day of this gargle am I supposed to drink?
80盎斯才能消除Z中毒的征
We are up to 80 ounces a day to counteract the symptoms, sir.
z查Z元素含量
Check palladium levels.
“血液毒性：24%”
Blood toxicity: 24%
看碇灰你^m使用F盔甲
It appears that the continued use of the Iron Man suit
中毒的速度愈快
is accelerating your condition.
另一K把能量板又耗p光了
Another core has been depleted.
它耗p得很快
God, they're running out quick.
我模M^每一N已知的元素
I have run simulations on every known element
]有一N能替代Z元素
and none can serve as a viable replacement for the palladium core.
你的rg和x褚呀不多了
You are running out of both time and options.
很不幸
Unfortunately,
你活命的b置也害死你
the device that's keeping you alive, is also killing you.
波小姐砹
Ms. Potts is approaching.
我建h你立刻告V…
I recommended that you inform her of...
o音
Mute.
你在_玩笑幔
Is this a joke?
你在想什N？
What are you thinking?
什N？
What?
你在想什N？
What are you thinking?
我在想我很忙，你又在生
Hey, I'm thinking I'm busy and you're angry about something.
你感冒了幔课也幌氡魅
Do you have the sniffles? I don't wanna get sick.Keep your distance
你是不是把…
Did you just donate
我所有的F代g收藏捐o…
our entire modern art collection to the...
美童子f？美童子f
- Boy Scouts of America?- Yes it is a...
那是很有意x的M
worthwhile organization.
我]有H自z查^木箱
I didn't physically check the crates,
不^基本上]e
but basically yes.
而且不是我的收藏
And it's not our collection,
是我的收藏，不要介意
it's my collection. No offense.
不，你知道幔
No, you know what I think
我有嘤“我”的收藏
I'm actually entitled to say Our collection,
因槲一了十年整理
considering the time that I've put in over 10 years curating that.
不^都是榱斯
It's a tax write-off, I needed that.
我只有8千零11件事…
You know, there's only about 8,011 things
必跟你
that I really need to talk to you about.
C械手，e恍神，Ｐ狞c
Dummy, hey stop now the bridgeport's already machining that part.
博[完全是浪Mrg
The expo is a gigantic waste of time.
你感冒]好之前得戴口罩
I need you to wear a surgical mask until you're feeling better,is that okay?
你很]Y貌耶
That's rude.
]有什N比博[ξ腋重要
There's nothing more important to me than the Expo.
那是我最P心的事情
It's my primary point of concern. I don't know why you...
博[只是你的s心作祟
The Expo is your ego gone crazy.
哇，你看看
Wow, look at that.
@是F代g，我要炱
That's modern art.That's going up.
你一定是在_玩笑
You've got to be kidding me.
我要R上把它炱
I'm gonna put this up right now.
斯塔克工Iy成一F
Stark is in complete disarray. Do you understand that?
我的股rq停板
No, our stocks have never been higher...
那是慕I者的角度砜
- Yes from a managerial standpoint. - Well if it's messy,then let's double back.
那就回去才那件事
Let's move on to another subject.
不，不行！
Oh, no no no,
你不准把~曼的拿下
you are not taking down the Barnett Newman and hanging that up!
我不是拿下恚只是取代它
I'm not taking it down, I'm just replacing it with this, let's see where I can get...
S你便，我想f的是…
Ok fine. My point is
我拿到L力l龅暮霞s
We have already awarded contracts to the windfarm people,
e提到L，你害我撇L
Don't say windfarm, I'm already feeling gassy.
有U馓理S的合s
And to the Plastic Plantation Tree,
那是你的c子
which was your idea by the way.
@些人都I我的薪水
Those people are on payroll, and you won't make a decision.
一切都是我的c子
Everything was my idea,
我不再P心自由派h}了
I don't care about the liberal agenda anymore.
真o聊的！
It's boring, boring!
我要o你一o聊警告
I'm giving you a boring order,
你去做   做什N？
you do it.I do what?
@c子太了，你砉芾砉司
Excellent idea, I just figured this out.You run the company.
是啊，我一直在著管理公司
- Yeah, i'm trying to run the company.- Pepper, I need you to run the company.
我不是叫你著去做
Well stop trying to do it and do it.
我是叫你H自去做
You will not give me the information that I need
我需要你去做
I need you to do it.
我一直著在做呀！
I am trying to do it but...
你都]在，我要你绦虚L
You're not listening to me. I'm trying to make you CEO.
你槭颤N不肯？
Why won't you let me?
你喝了不少，Π桑
Have you been drinking?
Γ~G素汁
Uh, chlorophyl.
我正式任命你樗顾克工I绦虚L
I hereby irrevocably appoint you
R上生效
Chairman and CEO of Stark Industries effective immediately.
就@
Yeah, done deal.
信不信由你，我想了很久
Actually, I've given this a fair amount of thought.
我甚至找了一些人x
believe it or not. Been doing a bit of a headhunting so to speak...
J真思考l是最m合的人x
trying to figure out who a worthy successor would be.
後聿虐lF…
And then I realized ...
就是你，一直都是你
it's you.It's always been you.
我以有法律}
I thought there'd be a legal issue,but actually
不^我是可以指定我的接班人的
I'm capable of appointing my successor,
也就是你
my successor being you.
恭喜了
Congratulations!
拿去，拿去嘛
Take it, just take it.
我不知道怎N想
I don't know what to think.
e想，喝下去
Don't think, drink.
“摩{哥大”
公C人砹耍^砗一些文件
Notary is here! Can you please come sign the transfer paperworks?
我正在痛宰霍根
I'm on Happy's count!
Σ黄   @是哪一招？
- Sorry.- What the hell was that?
@叫C合格Y，才流行
It's called mixed martial arts. It's been around for three weeks.
@叫下流拳簦流行很久了
It's called dirty boxing.There's nothing new about it.
我保C@是我唯一一次
I promise you this is the only time
你把你的公司Do我
I will ask you to sign over your company.
上名字的s
I need you to initial each box.
第一n，千fe把眼神移_…
Lesson one:Never take your eye off...
我不玩了
That's it I'm done.
你叫什N，小姐？
What's your name, lady?
妮坦莉?Zz曼
Rushman, Natalie Rushman.
^恚上擂_
Front and center, come in to the church.
你不是真的想要她…
No, you're seriously not gonna...
法官f了就算，我就是法官
If it pleases the Court, which it does.
]}
No problem.
抱歉，他@人比^…怪
I'm sorry. He's very eccentric.
什N？
What?
你能不能教她一下？
Can you give her a lesson?
]}
No problem.
致铮
What?
她是l？
Who is she?
她碜苑律部
She is from legal.
你再一直盯著她看
And she is potentially a very expensive sexual harassment lawsuit
就可能害你吃上性}_官司
if you keep ogling her like that.
我需要新的助理，老
I need an assistant boxer. I need an assistant.
我有三很有力的人x
Yes, and I have three excellent potential candidates
等你和他面
that are lined up and ready to beat you.
我]rg面
I don't have time to meet.
我F在就要一，我X得是她
I need someone now I feel like it's her.
^Σ皇
No it's not.
你有]有打^拳？   有
- You ever boxed before?- I have, yes.
像是搏艚∩聿伲
Like Tae Bo, booty boot camp,
塑身操？瑜咖之的？
crunch,something like that?
你的姓怎N拼，妮坦莉？
How do we spell your name Natalie?
R一U一S一H一M一A一N
R-U-S-H-M-A-N.
你要Google查找她？
What are you gonna google her now?
我以槲沂窃诙⒅她
I thought I was ogling her.
哇，她很害嘛
Oh wow. Very, very impressive individual...
你很o聊耶
You're so predictable, you know that?
她精通法Z、x大利Z和拉丁Z
she's fluent in French,Italian, Russian, Latin...
lf拉丁Z呀？
Who speaks Latin?
]有人f，那是快消失的Z言
No one speaks Latin. It's a dead language.
]有人f拉丁Z
You can read Latin or you can write, but you can't speak Latin so...
你在|京^模特幔
Did you model in Tokyo?
她就^
- Cause she modelled in Tokyo. - No.
我需要她，她泳闳
I need her, she's got everything that I need.
第一lF律：死盯著κ
Rule number one: Never take your eye off your opponent.
我的天啊！
Oh my God!
霍根！
Happy!
@就是我f的！
That's what I'm talking about.
我只是滑倒   是幔
I slipped.
真的
You did?
看起硐袷羌夹g性舻
Looks like a TKO to me.
我需要你的指印
Just, um, I need your impression.
你很沉，非常成熟…
You have quite reserved, I don't know...
我是f你的指y
I meant your fingerprints.
好啊
Right.
怎N樱
So, how're we doing?
棒呆了，就快搞定了
Great. Just half done,... hey.
你才是老
You're the boss.
有事幔斯塔克先生？
Will that be all, Mr. Stark?
]了
- No.- Yes.
]事了，Z小姐，xx你
That will be all, Ms. Rushman.Thank you very much.
我要@一
I want one.
不行
No.
摩{哥
g迎淼侥Welcome to the Historic Grand Prix of Monaco.
@啄淼馁事是特e精彩...
This year's race will be exciting...
@e是W洲
It's Europe,
不管l生什N事，其自然
whatever happens the next twenty minutes just go with it.
其自然？
just go with it？
斯塔克先生？
- Mr. Stark?- Hey
旅程利吧？
- How was your flight?- It was excellent.
很好，真的很高d到你
Oh it's nice to see you.
有位摩We have one photographer from the ACM
可以幔
if you don't mind.
你是r雇用她的？
When did this happen?
是你逼我的
You made me do it.
我逼你做什N？
I made you do what?
微笑，看@e
Smile and you. Look there.
e一直[臭
Stop acting constipated.
你的老毛病就是不改
- You are so predictable.- Do not inflate your nostrils.
你看起砻来袅耍
- Right this way.- Thanks, you look fantastic.
多xF
Why,thank you very much.
我知道我很不I，有什N行程？
But that's unprofessional. What's on the docket?
9c半有局
We have a 9.30 dinner.
太好了，我11c到
Perfect I'll be there at 11.
我的桌位？
Is this ours?
我可以搞定
It can be.
太好了，去搞定吧
Great, make it ours.
R斯克先生，你好幔
Mr. Musk, how are you?
恭喜你升   xx你
- Congratulations on the promotion.- Thank you very much.
伊隆，梅林引擎棒呆了
Elon, those Merlin engines are fantastic.
x了，我想打造力射C
Thanks. I got an idea for an electric jet.
真的假的？   真的
You do?
那就一起合作吧
Then we'll make it work.
你要按摩幔课医心萏估虬才
- You want a massage? - Oh god no I don't want a massage.- I'll have Natalie make an appointment.
我不要妮坦莉安排任何事
I do not want Natalie to do anything.
我不是故意不告V你
By the way I didn't mean to spring this on you.
多x了喔
Thank you very much.
你穿G色不是很好看
Green is not your best color.
托尼！是你幔
Anthony, is that you?
我最的砘铮Z斯汀?h默
- My least favorite person on earth,Justin Hammer. - How you doing?
你不是唯一_名的有X人
You're not the only rich guy here with a fancy car.
@是《浮A世界》的克莉z汀  你zJR？
You know Christine Everhart from Vanity Fair? You guys know each other?
Yes!
Γ但是K不熟
Yes, roughly.
α耍大新
BTW, big story,
斯塔克工I全新的绦虚L
The new CEO of Stark Industries.
恭喜了
Congratulations.
我不L你的被主R死
- My editor will kill me ... if I don't grab a quote for our Powerful Women issue.- Can I?- Sure.
她要在《浮A世界》ＴL我
She's actually doing a big spread on me for Vanity Fair.
我便她L你，Π桑
I thought I'd throw her a bone, you know.Right?
]e
Right.
她去年屯心帷白觥边^一次ＴL
She did quite a spread on Tony last year.
然後也了一篇
And she wrote a story as well.
令人印象深刻
It was very impressive.
得很好
That was good.
非常好   xx你
Very well done.
我要去洗手先   eG下我
- I'm gonna go wash.- Do not leave me.
老兄，你好幔   好得很
How you doing? You look great.
你懒   e靠@N近
Please, this is hard.
我能你，@是…
So is this the first time that...
天呀！
Jeez,
天啊，真海∈懿涣耍
Oh, god that's so awful.
…你在C後第一次面
Listen, it's the first time you've seen each other since the Senate?
自乃的合s被取消以後？ 不是，只是壕
- Since he got his contract revoked.- Actually, it's on hold.
我到的可不是@
That's not what I heard.
壕和取消有什N不同？
What's the difference between on hold and canceled?
事幔
The truth?
事是…
No. The truth is,
把答CP了吧
oh put that away,
事是…
The truth is
我想在你的博[展示a品
I'm actually hoping to present something at your expo.
如果你l明能用的|西
Well, if you invent something that works,I'll make sure I get you a slot.
我一定替你保留展示d
- Mr. Stark?- Yes.
他只是在_玩笑   桌子安排好了
- He's kidding,...- Your corner table is ready.
今年我有一C
I actually have a slot, yes I do.
h默需要“C”啦   不是啦
Hammer needs a 'slot.'
我常常_玩笑
- We'll give him. - We kid, we're kidders.
“血液毒性：53%”
有更糟的c子幔
Got any other bad ideas?
我和托尼…
Tony and I, Tony,
我弁心幔他也畚
I love Tony Stark.
我不是κ
Tony loves me.We're not competitors.
他退出售行I以後…
Him being out of the picture created tremendous
e接促使h默工I加速l展
opportunity for Hammer Industries you know.
我和托尼之g…
Everything that Tony and I do is a healthy...
碛幸惠v就是要比
What's the use of having and owning a race car,
…有的是良性
...competition.
不然碛匈要致铮
...if you don't drive it?
他要？
Is he driving?
妮坦莉，妮坦莉！
Natalie! Natalie!
你知道他要幔
- Yes?- Did you know about this?
我也是F在才知道的
This is the first time I hear it.
他不能
That cannot happen.
我t解，我怎N湍悖
Absolutely, I understand. How can I help you?
霍根呢？   他在外面
- Where is Happy? - He's waiting outside.
去找他，我需要霍根
Ok get him, I need Happy.
R上就去
Right away.
我和托尼不是κ郑懂幔
Tony is, we're, you know...We're not competitive.You know what I mean?
恕我失陪一下
You know what?Can you excuse me just one second?
你能不能把你的念o我？
- Why don't you just read me what you wrote?- I will.
我的，但我得先打通
- After I make one quick phone call.- Where are you going?
你要去哪e？
I got some caviar coming.
等一下有~子u哦
This is great stuff,
我R上回
I'll be right back!
那笨蛋去道e面!
That asshole just goes inside the track!
天呀！
God!
快走！
Go, go!
坐好了
Hang on!
把公事箱o我   拿去
- Give me the case.- Here, take it.
匙呢？   在我的口袋
- Where is the key!- It's in my pocket.
有！
Car!
天啊
Oh, my God!
你]事吧？
Are you okay?
]事
Yeah.
你是想撞我是撞他？
Were you heading for me or him?
我只想他
I wanted to scare him.
因槲曳植磺宄！
Cause I can't tell!
你啦？   更好的保全…
Are you out of your mind?
快上！   我受到攻簦
- Better security.- Get in the car!
i^！   我需要更好的保全！
- I was attacked!- You're a jerk!- We need better security.
快上！
Get in the car!
我要更好的保全！真G
Better security measures!God it's embarrassing.
赡淼谝淮涡菁佟
First vacation in two years.
我的天啊！
Oh  my god!
我撞到他了！
I got him!
再撞他一次，再一次！
Hit him again, hit him again!
把箱子o我
Give me the case.
我撞到他了！
I hit him!
把公事箱拿去！
Give me the case!
快拿o他！
Give him the case!
e再撞了！
Stop banging the car!
天啊！
Oh, god!
把公事箱o我，拜！
Give me the case! Please!
快c！
Come on!
你了！
You'll lose!
你了，斯塔克
You'll lose. You'll lose, Stark.
我查^他的指y
We've checked his fingerprints.
啥都]有，B名字都查不到
Nothing.Not even a name.
我要去哪e？
Where are we going?
那e
There.
我甚至不_定他f英Z
He may not understand us.
他B一字都]f
In fact, he has not even spoken.
5分
Five minutes.
挺先M的科技
Pretty decent tech.
不^D速有c低
Cycles per second were a little low.
你大可以把D速加倍
You could have doubled up your rotations.
反能量穿^x子化You focused the Repulsor energy through ionized plasma channels.
有用，但效率不高
It's effective. Not very efficient.
不^是挺不e的仿冒品
But it's passable enough though.
我不懂，只要微I don't get it. With a little fine tuning
你就能靠它不少X
you could've made a solid paycheck,
你可以uo北n、中和伊朗
if you sold it to North Korea,China,
或是直接在黑市兜售
Iran, or gone right to the black market.
看砟愕呐笥讯际琴\匪之徒
You look like you got friends in low places.
你的家族是小偷和屠夫
You come from a family of thieves and butchers.
你跟每一罪人一
And now,like all guilty men,
想要重你的v史
try to rewrite your own history
忘了斯塔克家族害死的人命
and you forget all the lives that Stark family has destroyed.
我的OD是哪偷淼模
Speaking of thieves,where did you get this design?
我父H，安|?f科
My father.Anton Vanko.
]^他
Well I've never heard of him.
你]死是因槲腋赣H
My father is the reason you're alive.
我]死是因槟阆⑺牢s失
The reason I'm alive is cause you had a shot,you took it and you missed.
是幔
Did I?
如果你能上帝流血
If you can make god bleed
人就不相信他
people will cease to believe him.
水中有血E，就引眭~
And there will be blood in the water.and the sharks will come.
我只要坐在@e看
The truth, all they have to do is sit and watch
世人就把你吞噬
as the world will consume you.
你要在哪e看世人把我吞噬？
Where will you be watching the world consume me from?
]e，你的牢房
That's right.
我送你一K香皂
A prison cell.I'll send you a bar of soap.
托尼，我奉送你一句
Hey Tony, before you go,
Z中毒的死法…很痛苦
palladium in the chest,painful way to die.
@C明他的科技被仿效
It's just unbelievable it proves the genie is out of the bottle
他s像o^n
and this man has no idea what he's doing
他把Fb作玩具
He thinks of the Iron Manweapon as a toy.
斯塔克先生在C上很Q地f
I was at a hearing where Mr. Stark in fact was adamant
F盔甲不在任何地方出F
that these suits can't exist,anywhere else, don't exist anywhere else,never will exist anywhere else
至少在未淼5至10年取
at least for 5-10 years and here we are in Monaco
但我在摩 realizing, uh-oh, these suits exist now
o音
Mute.
f真的，他C章o我
He should be giving me a medal.That's the truth.
那是什N？
What is that?
你在C上的餐c
This is your in-flight meal.
@是你做的？
- Did you just make that?- Yeah.
Γ你以槲疫@3小r在致铮
Where do you think I've been for three hours?
托尼？
Tony ...
你有什N在m著我？
What are you not telling me?
我完全不想回家
I don't want to go home ...at all.
取消我的生日派
Let's cancel my birthday party and
反正我在W洲
We're in Europe.
不如去威尼斯住西普尼店
Let's go to Venice, Chipriani.
得幔   得
- Remember?- Oh yes.
住在那e…
It's a great place to...
F在不是好rC…有益身w健康
I don't think this is the right time.be healthy.
一大堆子要收拾
We are in a kind of a mess.
]e，所以才是好rC
Yeah but maybe that's why it's the best time.
我身绦虚L必坐公司
Wow, I think as the CEO I need to
你身绦虚L有嗬度假
show up. - As CEO you are entitled to a
度假？   T工度假
- leave?- Company retreat.
在@No要P^？
A retreat? During a time like this?
我只要再充就想出k法
I'm just saying to recharge our batteries and figure it all out.
不是每人都靠池^活
Not everybody runs on batteries, Tony.
“享用洋芋泥”
Have fun with the Pee
停步  囚犯
Prisoner stop!
你要做什N？
What are you doing?
他砹耍
Hey, here he is!
他砹
There he is!
很高d你砹耍g迎
What an absolute pleasure.Welcome.
真是的
Goodness gracious,
把我朋友的手D解_
can we get the handcuffs off my friend here?
原我，我是你的超粉z
Forgive me, I'm sorry.I'm such a huge fan of yours.
我不想你留下挠∠
I didn't wanna...make a first impression like this.
他又不是游铮他是人
He's not an animal. Come on.He's a human being.
xx你
Thank you.
W_吧
Leave us.
我不有事
Oui, oui, I'm fine.
我叫Z斯汀?h默
My name is Justin Hammer.
我想跟你做c生意
I'd like to do some business with you.
坐
Please sit.
吃吧，芸私裉煊惺颤N菜色？
Dig in.What do we have today, Jack?
q~佐u汁
Some salmon carpaccio, sir.
q~佐u汁？
Salmon carpaccio?
你要什N我都有
Anything you want here, we got it.
我喜g先吃甜c
I like my dessert first.
@是娜藩市空\送淼
I had this flown in from San Francisco.
不^是x式甜c
It's Italian though.
有C霜淇淋
Organic ice cream.
我非常鄢蕴鹗
I got a sweet tooth.
看砟阋埠芟⑺劳心?斯塔克
Apparently you do too for Tony Stark.
我看到你在道攻羲
When I saw what you do to Tony Stark on that track
你像天兵神⒄驹谒面前
how you stepped up to him in front of god and everybody,
大家都X得太神了
that was wow!
你向我鬟_一Y
You spoke to me was what you did.
我也知道你知道我一定
And I know that you knew that I'd be listening.
所以我不能他把你送走
This is why I couldn't bear to have you shipped off to god knows where.
白白浪M你的才能
It would've been such a waste of talent.
不^我想o你一建h
But if I might make a suggestion you know you don't just go
不要就@优苋ハ⑺浪
and try to kill the guy. I think...
我的想法是…
if I may,
要是我就扼⑺的成就
you go after his legacy.That's what you should kill.
我有很多地方很像
You and me we're a lot alike in a lot of ways.
唯一的不同是我有Y源
The only difference between you and I
我J槟阈枰我的Y源
is that I have resources.I think, if I may,
你的靠山，一位助人
you need my resources.Someone behind you.
我想那人
A benefactor.I'd like to be that guy.
你f英Z幔
Okay.Do you speak English,
我可以找一翻g
because I can get a translator.
我不_定你懂我f的
I don't know if you've been understanding everything I'm saying.
很好的人
Very good, man.
非常好，老兄
很好，老兄
Very good, man.
什N事？
Yes.
我要我的小B
I want my bird.
小B？你要一b小B？
A bird?
我要我的小B
- You want a bird?- I want my bird.
我可以o你十b小B
I can get you bird I can get you ten birds.
我要我的小B
I want my bird.
好，]有不可能的事
Okay,nothing's impossible.
你是f你在俄_斯的小B？
I could, are we talking about...is this a bird back in Russia?
管l生摩Yes, but the fundamentals of the company are still very, very strong
本公司的基A仍然很牢固
despite the events in Monaco.
美社要你l言
The AP wants a quote.
把@份明稿髡娼o他
Oh, oh, fax them.
他在哪e？
Where is he?
他不想被打_
He doesn't wanna be disturbed.
他在窍
He's downstairs.
但是他一直出r
His continuing erratic behavior
大|疑他能否保o我
may lead many people to ask themselves can this man still protect us?
Fb一直在保o我
Iron Man never stopped protecting us.
摩The events in Monaco prove that.
搜ね戤
Query complete, sir.
安|?f科是K物理W家
Anton Vanko was a Soviet physicist
1963年叛逃到美
who defected to the United States in 1963.
但是他被指控是g
However, he was accused of espionage and was
1967年被逐出境
deported in 1967.
他鹤右练惨彩俏锢W家
His son, Ivan, who is also a physicist,
因樨售Kr期
was convicted of selling
武器材料o巴基斯坦
Soviet-era weapons-grade plutonium
被判在科佩斯克Oz服刑15年
to Pakistan and served 15 years in Kopeisk prison.
]有其它
No further records exist.
托尼？
Tony,
你得上前亚菘刂谱
you gotta get upstair and get on top of this situation right now.
我一整天都在和民兵通
Listen, I've been on the phone with the National Guard all day,
f服他不要_坦克^
trying to talk them out of rolling tanks and the PCH
撞破你的大T，拿走@些
knocking down your front door and taking these.
他想拿走你的F盔甲
They're gonna take your suits, Tony,
他械酶你玩[
they're sick of the games.
你f20年]人能碛羞@N科技
You said nobody else would possess this technology for twenty years.
猜怎N著…昨天就有人碛兴
Well guess what,somebody else had it yesterday.
而且不再是理
It's not theoretical anymore.
你有在幔
Are you listening to me?
你好吧？
Are you okay?
走吧
Let's go.
你]事吧？
Are you alright?
我要到我的k公桌
Yeah I should go to my desk.
看到雪茄盒幔   看到了
- See that cigar box?- Yes.
那是Z能量板
It's palladium.
@玩意冒幔
Is that supposed to be smoking?
中子受p，是方舟反t壁在冒
If you must know it's neutron damage.it's from that reactor wall.
@玩意在你w龋
You had this in your body?
你脖子上的字i又是怎N回事？
And how about the high-tech crossword puzzle on your neck?
擦的痕E
Rogue rash.
xx你
Thank you.
你在看什N？
What are you looking at?
我在看你
I'm looking at you.
你]必要一人救世主
You wanna do this whole lone gunslinger act
你不必光靠自己
and it's unnecessary.You don't have to do this alone.
我也很想相信你f的
You know I wish I could believe that.I really do.
但是你得信任我
But you gotta trust me.
一般人ξ矣姓`解…
Contrary to popular belief,
我很清楚我在做什N
I know exactly what I'm doing.
~s皇后^
@是我的火工S，我的寒舍
This is where we do it.This is my humble abode.
你可以安o地工作
You can work in absolute peace.
死人很好玩吧？]有毫Γ
Must be kinda fun to be dead, right?No pressure.
它在那e，都挺d^的
Ah, here they are.They're excited,
它可以Sr作
they're combat ready.
我也S算e了一些Y料
I may have done a few miscalculations and
太急著利用原型大量u造
rushed the prototype, but sue me,
]k法，我是急性子
I'm enthusiastic.
S便到看看
Go ahead, take a look around.
你最好不要那N做
Oh, you don't wanna do that.
我要先O定一些密a
You'll be able to access that as soon as we generate some encrypted passcodes.
你才能_始操作
Can we generate some encrypted passcodes?
快去O定密ao他使用
Let's get some of those...
“入密a”
“准SM入”
encrypted passcodes, Jack.
算了
Nevermind.
哇，好吧  好拥
Wow, okay. Good stuff.
什N？
Sorry?
你的w是狗屎
Software shit.
你很害
You're good.
你就@悠平饬朔阑
You really blasted and passed the firewall there.
我o你看你要在哪e工作
Let me show you where you're gonna be working primarily.
看吧，仔看吧
Go ahead, take a look.
你看看，很棒，Π桑
Take a good look at that.That's something, isn't it?
那些F盔甲只是展示品
You know they're really just for show and tell.
每套r值1|2千5百70f…
They're 125.7 million a pop.
ey搞！
so... Wait! Oh, gosh.
老天，快找人上兔
Jesus Christ. Get somebody up here.
那是That's where the pilot goes.
不^我找不到自者
I'm having a tough time finding volunteers.
我搞定，ey碰
I'll take care of that just leave it.
你要它做什N？
What you want them do?
L期碚f，我要它我…
Long term,I want them to put me in
能和防部下25年的合s
the Pentagon for the next 25 years.
我要Fb看起硐窆哦
I wanna make Iron Man look like an antique.
我要去斯塔克博[
I wanna go to that Stark Expo
在托尼的前院拉屎，你懂幔
and take a dump on Tony's front yard.- You know what I'm talking about?
我k得到，]}
- Ya I can do that.- Yes?- No problem.
棒呆了，我喜g
Hey, fabulous I love it.
我就f他是我的救星吧
This is our guy. Didn't I tell you?
我有A感
I had a feeling.
“Z舛龋89%"
你今晚想戴哪一支手l？
Do you know which watch you'd like to wear tonight Mr. Stark?
我等一下看
I'll give them a look.
我取消派ΓΠ桑
I should cancel the party now?
大概吧
Probably.
是啊，因檎娴摹
Yeah, cause it's, um...
不是r候
Ill-timed.
@l出e`息
Right, sends the wrong message.
很不恰
Inappropriate.
蛄幔
Is that dirty enough for you?
金色表面、棕色l
Gold faced with the brown band...
我看看那支e家牌手l
The Jaeger.I'll give that a look.
拿^
Bring them over here.
我要戴那支，你可以…
I'll take that.Why don't you...
老f，我摸不清你的底
I gotta say it's hard to get a read on you.
你碜阅难e？
Where are you from?
法律部T
Legal.
我能你一假O性}幔
Can I ask you a question hypothetically?
@}有c怪
It's a bit odd.
如果@是你最後一次生日派
If this was your last birthday party
你怎Nc祝？
you're ever gonna have how would you celebrate it?
想跟l做什N就做什N
I'd do whatever I wanted to do.with whoever I wanted to do it.
是的L官，我t解
Yes, sir, I understand.
不，]有@必要，我理
No, sir, that will not be necessary.I'll handle it.
我保C24小r
Sir, I personally guarantee that within 24 hours
Fb就回到他的位
Iron Man will be back on watch.
嘿，小辣椒
Hey, Pepper ...
我要走了，我得出去透透
I'm gonna go get some air.
怎N了？
What's wrong?
我不知道怎N做
I don't know what to do.
@是在_玩笑吧
You gotta be kidding me.
蛄耍我要…
That's it, I'm gonna make a...
不，e打o任何人
No, no, don't call anyone.
太扯了，我才替他作了保C耶
This is ridiculous I just stuck my neck up for this guy.
我知道，我搞定
I know. I get it. I'm gonna handle it okay,just let me handle it.
快c搞定，不然我就H自
Handle it, or I'm gonna have to.
我最常被的}是：
You know the question I get asked most often is
你穿了F盔甲要怎N上所？
Tony how do you go to the bathroom with the suit?
就像@
Just like that.
@砘锾_家庭派ΓΠ桑
Does this guy know how to throw a party or what?
我勰恪
I love you.
不可思h，xx你，托尼
Unbelievable. Thank you so much,Tony,
xx你安排@N美好的夜晚
we all thank you so much for such a
我f晚安了，xx大家光R
wonderful night. We're gonna say Good night now and thank you all for coming.
不…不…等等…等等…
No, no, wait, we can't,
我都]切蛋糕、吹T
we didn't bring out the cake we didn't blow out the candle.
你已失控了   我失控了？
- You're out of control okay- I'm out of control?
相信我   你才美得失控呢
- Trust me on this one okay?- You're out of control gorgeous
上床睡X了  H我一下，你知道你想要
- It's time to go to bed.- Give me a little smooch.
你才尿在F盔甲e
Come on you know you want to.
我知道，它有^V系y
You just peed the suit.
^V出淼乃可以喝
- I know, has a filtration system.- It's not sexy.- You can drink that water.
大家回家吧，r候不早了
Just send everybody home, okay.
你f了算
- It's time to...- If you say so.
好幔
Okay, I'll take this.
我拿@，你拿@
You take that.
小辣椒波
Pepper Potts.
她f的Γ派Y束了
She's right.The party is over.
派1半小r前就Y束了
Then again the party was over for me like an hour and a half ago.
但事後派㈧丁15分後_始
The after party starts in 15 minutes!
如果有人…包括小辣椒…不喜g
And if anybody, Pepper, doesn't like it,
大T就在那e
there's the door.
G！
Shoot!
再G！
我恚
Me!
我猜她喜g西瓜哥哥
I think she wants the Gallanger!
你打中了！
There you go!
我只要f一次
I'm only gonna say this once.
L出去
Get out!
你不配穿F盔甲，掉它
You don't deserve to wear one of these.Shut it down!
小戈
Goldstein.
是的，斯塔克先生
Yes, Mr. Stark?
e怕，音方o它摧下去
Give me a fat beat to beat my buddy's ass to...
我叫你把F盔甲掉
I told you to shut it down.
把它放回去，免得有人受
Now, put that thing back where you found it before someone gets hurt.
真硌剑
Really?
抱歉，Fb不需要助手
Sorry pal, but Iron Man doesn't have a sidekick.
吃我@一招！
Suck at this!
玩蛄幔
Had enough?
妮坦莉！   波小姐
- Natalie!- Ms. Potts ...
少砹耍我早就看穿你的
Don't you Ms. Potts me. I'm on to you.
你砹艘葬峋汀
You know what, ever since you came here...
小辣椒！
Pepper!
快W人吧！
Let's get out of here!
你要@玩意？
You want it?
拿去呀！
Take it!
出去！
Out!
把手放下
Put your hand down.
你自以橛挟Fb的料幔
You think you got what it takes to wear that suit?
我不必打泶蛉
We don't have to do this, Tony.
你想C器，_火呀
You wanna be a war machine?Take your shot.
快放下！   _火呀
Put it down! shot.
放下恚   不！
- You're gonna take your shot?- Put it down, now!
放下恚   快_火！
- Drop it Tony- Take it!
鄣氯A空基地
@是詹姆斯?_德中校
Tower this is Lt. Col. James Rhodes
C鲆|3e外M
eastbound for 3 miles,...
要求降落在22停C坪
中校
Colonel.
少校
Major.
是啊
Yeah.
把它нM去吧
Let's take it inside.
Q空@^域！
Clear the area.
先生！你奶鹛鹑ι舷恚
Sir! I'm gonna have to ask you to exit the donut.
我不想加入你的超人男孩Fw
I told you I don't wanna join your super secret boyband.
我得，你什N都是自己
No, see, I remember, you do everything myself.
Y果怎N樱
How's it workin out for you?
Y果…Y果…
It's... It's... It's...
抱歉，我不想引起你的`
I'm sorry, I don't wanna get off on the wrong foot,
我看你的眼罩是眼睛？
do I look in the patch or the eye?
老f，我有c宿醉
Honestly I'm a bit hungover
我不_定你是真人是幻X
I'm not sure if you're real or if...
我是真人
I am very real.
我是你^最真的人
I'm the realest person you're ever gonna meet.
我真走\，@e的T工呢？
Just my luck. Where is the staff here?
@看起聿惶妙
Oh, that's not lookin too good.
我有^更糟的r
It's getting worse.
我Q空整^域
We've secured the perimeter,
不^最好不要花太多rg
but I don't think we should hold it for too much longer.
你被_除了
You're fired.
@由不得你Q定
That's not up to you.
托尼，@是洛曼Z芙探T
Tony... I want you to meet agent Romanoff.
我是神盾局的P底T
I'm a Shield shadow
我知道你病了
and I was tasked to you
福瑞局L就派我碛^察你
by Dr. Fury.
你最好向我道歉
I suggest you apologize.
你一直都很忙
You've been very busy.
你把女助手任命绦虚L
Made your girl your CEO,
把你的a到送人
you've given away all your stuff.
你朋友穿著F盔甲w走！
You let your friend fly away with your suit.
要不是我t解r…
- If I didn't know better...- You don't know better.
我]有o他，是他走的
I didn't give it to him.He took it.
什N？是他走的？ 你是Fb，他就@走？
He took it? You're Iron Man and he just took it?
他痛扁你一D，走你的F盔甲
Little brother walked in there kicked your ass and took your suit?
@有可能幔
Is that possible?
根斯塔克先生的安z程式
According to Mr. Stark's database security guidelines
系y可以避免未授嗍褂
There are redundancies to prevent unauthorized usage.
你要我做什N？
What do you want from me?
我要你做什N？
What do we want from you? No, no, no!
是你要我做什N？
What do you want from me.
你成我得理的}人物
You have become a problem, a problem I have to deal with.
你可能想e了
Contrary to your belief,
我的世界不是@著你\行的
you are not the center of my universe. - Yeah I get it.
好，我知道了
I have bigger problems than you
西南^有比你更大的}
in the Southwest region to deal with.
打吧
Hit him.
你是要拿走我的IK去u幔
Are you gonna steal my kidney and sell it?
可不可以e再做@些怪事
Could you please not do anything awful for 5 seconds?
她才ξ易隽耸颤N？
What did you just do to me?
我是榱四愫
What did we just do for you.
那是二氧化，能p你的病徵
That's lithium dioxide. It's gonna take the edge off.
我想你回去工作
We're trying to get you back to work.
再o我珊形揖好起
Give me a couple of boxes and I'll be right as rain.
那不是解，只能p病徵
It's not a cure, it's just to break the symptoms.
看硪治好你K不容易
Then the lag is gonna be an easy fix.
相信我，我知道，我t解r
Trust me I know I'm good at this stuff.
我一直在找Z元素的替代品
I've been looking for a suitable replacement for palladium.
我^每N元素的每NM合
I've tried every combination, every permutation of every known element.
我是砀嬖V你，你]全部^
Well, I'm here to tell you you haven't tried them all.
你有快f！
Hey, hey, hey.Special delivery.
使命必_！
Candygram!
我Я|西o你
I brought you something.
]e
Oh, yeah.
我找到你的小B，兄弟！
We got you the bird, pal.
@不是我的小B
This is not my bird.
什N意思？@就是那只小B
What do you mean?That's the bird.
我靠很多PS才找到的
I pulled a lot of strings to get this bird.
@是只很棒的小B
It's a great bird.
而且很漂亮
It's a beautiful bird.
大老h亩砹_斯找淼囊！
We got this all the way from Russia.
老兄，@不是我的小B
Hey man, it's not my bird.
就算不是你那只小B
Well listen, even if it's not the bird,
@只小B也很漂亮
I mean this is a gorgeous bird.
e@N固
I mean, look, don't get so attached to things,
你得W放手
learn to let go.
等一下，芸耍那是什N？
Wait a minute.Jack, what is that?
那…那不是^盔，那是什N？
Is that...That's not a helmet. What is that?
伊凡？那是什N？
Ivan... What's this?
芸耍
Jack?
那是^盔幔靠雌聿幌
Is that a helmet? It doesn't look like a helmet to me.
你要怎N把^塞M去？
How are you supposed to get a head in there?
芸耍你的^塞得M去幔
Jack, could you put your head in there?
不行
No.
著把^塞M去
Try to put your head in there.
看，著塞M去
Go ahead, try to put your head in there.
伊凡，他的^塞不M去
See Ivan, he can't put his head in there. That's...
那不是^盔，那是一w^
That's not a helmet, it's a head.
我得把一人bM去耶
I need to put a guy in there.
@套F盔甲要能穿，你懂幔
I need to fit a person in that suit, you understand?
u控F士兵比^好
Drone better.
u控F士兵比^好？
What? Drone better?Why is drone better?
槭颤N比^好？
Why drone better?
人出e
People make problem.
相信我，u控比^好
Trust me,drone better.
伊凡，你知道我喜g你
Ivan, you know I like you.
我替你弄到小B
I got you the bird.
你f]}
You said no problem.
是你f的，你f]}
That's what you said to me, you said no problem.
F在我要F盔甲
Now I need suits.
政府要的是F盔甲
The government wants suits.
像Fb一樱∧愣幔
Like Iron Man, you understand?
那是大家要的！
That's what the people want.
@铀才高d
That's what's gonna make them happy.
老兄
Hey, man...
e@N固
Don't get to attached to things.
你得W放手
Learn to let go.
@些F士兵最好能一炮而t
These drones better steal the show, Ivan.
懂幔克最好能我出名！
You understand? They better rock my world, Ivan.
不可思h
Unbelievable.
@右⒆h院就不再┪
This ought to get the Senate off my ass.
它能用幔
It's functional?
完全能绦腥
Fully mission-capable.
很好，h默替它b上武器
Good. Get Hammer down here to weaponize it.
L官？
Sir?
h默要在博[上展示新武器
Justin Hammer's making a weapons presentation at the expo.
我要用@碜鲩_
We'd like this to introduce it.
我不J椴┯[m合…
Sir, I don't believe that the expo is...
中校，世人需要看到@玩意
Colonel, the world needs to see this fast.
我必M足他
We've got to make this happen.
是的，④，但是…
Yes general, but the...
@也是命令
It's also an order.
遵命，L官
Yes, sir.
值煤茫中校，家以你s
Good work, Colonel.You've made your country proud.
xx你，L官
Thank you, sir.
你胸口的那玩意…
That thing in your chest
是根未完成的科技做的
is based on unfinished technology.
不，它是完成品
No it was finished,it's never been particularly effective until
我把它s小後才起了功效
I've miniaturized it and put it in my...
不，你爸f方舟反t…
No, Howard said that the arc reactor was
只是更ゴ蟮目萍嫉奶板
a stepping stone to something greater.
他年湔归_一瞿芰扛
He was about to kick off an energy race
所有κ滞m莫及
That was gonna dwarf the arms race.
他摸索到了一N超能量的^w
He was on to something big,something so big
核子反t在相^之下…像是一枚3A池
that it was gonna make the nuclear reactor look like a AAA battery.
只有他幔
Just him?
安|?f科也有⑴c吧？
Or was Anton Vanko in on this too?
安|?f科就像~板的另一面
Anton Vanko is the other side of that coin.
他J槟鞘前l大的方法
Anton saw it as a way to get rich.
你父HlF後就把他逐出境
When your father found out he had him deported.
老俄lF他]有用
When the Russians found out he couldn't
就把他下放到西伯利
deliver they shipped his ass off to Siberia
20年磉^著酗酒世的生活
and he spent the next 20 years on a vodka fuel rage.
π『⒊砷L不是很好
Not quite the environment you wanna raise a kid in.
你在摩His son you had the misfortune of crossing paths with in Monaco.
你f我]全部^
You told me I hadn't tried everything.
什N意思？我]^什N？
What do you mean I haven't tried everything?What haven't I tried?
他f只有你有Y源和智慧…
He said that you were the only person with the means and knowledge
去完成他_始的
to finish what he started.
他@Nf？
He said that?
他f的是你幔
Are you that guy?Huh? Are you?
如果是你…
Because if you are then
你就能解_你的心^之i
you can solve the riddle of your heart.
我不知道你是怎N知道@些事
I don't know where you get your information,
但他K不是很肯定我
but he wasn't my biggest fan.
你得你爸什N？
What do your remember about your dad huh?
他很冷漠，重心
He was cold, he was calculating...
]f^他畚
He never told me he loved mehe never even told me he liked me.
也]f^他喜g我
So it's a little tough for me to digest
我很y相信他f我能改未
what're you telling me he said the whole future is riding on me
而且他把@任鞒薪o我 我不明白
and he's passing it down... I don't get that.
他最高d的一天是把我送到寄宿W校
We're talking about a guy whose happiest daywas when he shipped me off to boarding school.
K不是@
That's not true.
那N很@然你比我更t解我爸
Well, then clearly you know my dad better than I did.
事上]e
As a matter of fact I did.
他是成立神盾局的成T之一
He was one of the founding members of The Shield.
什N？
What?
我2c有s
I got a two o'clock.
等等…@是什N？
Wait, wait, what's this?
你可以，Π桑
- Okay, you're good, right?- No I'm not good.
不，我不可以
You got this, right?
你能解_，Π桑
Got what?
我B要解_什N都不知道
I don't even know what I'm supposed to get.
娜塔莎^m在斯塔克工IP底
Natasha will remain a floater at Stark with her cover intact
你得考森T吧？
and you remember Agent Colson right?
得
Yeah.
噢，托尼
Oh, and Tony...
住，我盯著你
Remember, I got my eye on you.
我已切嗨有的通
We've disabled all communications,
不能ν饴M
no contact with the outside world.
祝好\
Good luck.
拜
Please...
首先，我需要做w能
First thing I need a little body work.
我在室工作一下
I'll put in a little time at the lab.
如果你能派手下到星巴克
If you could send of your goon squad down to the Coffee Bean
替我I些食物和料就更好
across the street or Starbucks, that'll be nice.
@不是我的
I'm not here for that.I've been authorized by
福瑞局L命令我用任何手段…
Director Fury to use any means necessary
你留在@e
to keep you on premises.
如果你想x_或是耍什N花招
- If you attempt to leave - Right - or play any games
我用舭舭涯汶昏
I will taze you and watch
看看你在地上流口水
Supernanny while you drool into the carpet. Okay?
我想我知道了
I think I got it, yeah.
享受你今晚的钒
Enjoy your evening's entertainment.
“霍A德?斯塔克所有物”
@就是它的能量碓幔
Think this is the power source?
少校，@不是科W
Major, this is not a scientific exercise.
Ｐ陌盐淦餮b上去，好幔
Let's just focus on arming it, alright?
是的，L官
Yes, sir.
好耶！
Oh, yes!
好耶！好耶！
Oh, yes, yes, yes!
今天是我生日幔
Is it my birthday?
不是吧？你做了什N？
You gotta.. what did you do?What did you do?
@是我想的那玩意幔
Is this what I think it is?
是的
Yes it is.
我要知道你能替我做什N
Hammer, I want to know what you're gonna do for us.
我要替你做什N？
What am I gonna do for you?
我要先替你的w升
First thing I'm gonna do for you is
我f的不是@，h默！
I'm gonna upgrade your software,
我f的是火力
I'm talking about firepower.
那你就找θ肆
Well you're talking to the right guy.
九米半自邮
Claridge Hi-Tec semi-automatic 9 mm pistol.
太d了？我同意
Too downtown?I agree.
M24霰，手由咸
M-24 shotgun pump action.
每匣五l子
5-round magazine, but you know what, you're not a hunter.
你又不是C人，我在f什N？
What am I talking about?
我把它G掉
I'm getting rid of it.
@是比利r制FN2000nh
This is the FN-2000 from Belgium.
比利r人不是只做松
They do make something better than waffles.
太了，不^你好像不M意
It's beautiful, but I can tell this isn't disco enough for you
所以我把它放在旁
so I'm gonna put it right here.
@是40米口搅
You're looking at a Milkor 40 mm grenade launcher.
能l射催I、F
Tear gas, smoke.
ｉT用Ω舵移
Hippie control.You're tough.
你的要求很高喔
Let me tell you something,
我告V你，大小很重要
Size does matter.
不要信e人f不重要
Don't let anyone tell you different.
@是M134C，6根管
This is an M134 7.62 minigun.Six individual barrels.
一就能人消散
The torso taker, powder maker.
士兵都蚍Q殡蚊香或泡泡
Our boys in uniform call it Uncle Gazpacho or Puff the Magic Dragon.
好吧
Okay.
@些是古巴雪茄
These are the Cubans baby.
高希霸，蒙特克e斯托
These are the Cohibas, the Montecristos...
@是尾蛇w，附b旋L炸
That's a kinetic-kill sidewinder vehicle with a secondary cyclotrimethylenetrinitramine RDX burst.
足以炸б蛔碉堡
It's capable of busting a bunker under
以及藏在更底下的碉堡
the bunker you just busted.
它再明一c就自己
If it were any smarter it would write a book.
^Ρ刃≌f《尤利西斯》更D
A book that would make Ulysses look like it was written in crayon.
而且自己xo你
And would read it to you.
@是我的艾菲F塔
This is my Eiffel Tower,
我的拉赫曼尼Z夫第三交曲
This is my Rachmaninoff's Third.
我的典之作
My Pieta. It's completely
造型雅，美到不行
elegant, it's bafflingly beautiful.
可以把任何建B物夷槠降
And it's capable of reducing the population of any standing structure to zero.
我把它命名椤扒捌蕖
I call it the Ex-Wife.
@是我最好的武器
That's the best I got.
你到底要不要？
How are you gonna do this?
o我暗示，你就像Give me something.You're like a sphinx.
我解不_你@i
I can't read you.
我要了
I think I'll take it.
哪一款？
Which one?
全部
All of it.
All of it?
“方舟反t f科-斯塔克”
“K科W家叛逃”
_拉
Action.
一切都能透^科技_成
Everything is achievable through technology.
更好的生活、健康的身w
Better living,robust health.
以及人v史上第一次…
And for the first time in human history...
S持世界和平的可能性
the possibility of world peace.
我是霍A德?斯塔克
I'm Howard Stark. And everything you'll need for the future,
你在未硇枰的一切都在@e
can be found right here.
未沓鞘校棵魅罩都？
City of Future,
未沓恰等一下
City of Tomorrow? Hang on.
我是霍A德?斯塔克
I'm Howard Stark.
你在未硇枰的一切都在@e
And everything you'll need in the future can be found right here.
我想H自樗顾克工I…
So, from all of us in Stark Industries I would like to personally...
托尼，你在致铮磕鞘鞘颤N？
Tony? What are you doing back there?What is that?
放回去，放回原淼牡胤剑
Put it back.Put it back where you got it from.
你呢？
Where is your mother?
莉！
Maria...
快走…快走…
Go on, go, go, go...
好了，可以了
Sorry I think we got the...
我要M恚然後…
I'll come in in there...
你在等我幔
Are you waiting on me?
我想代表全公司你看…
So from all of us in Stark Industries I'd like to personally show you...
我的屁股
my ass.
我想…我是f…
I'd like to... This...I can't...
都拍完了，不是幔
We have this don't we?
@工作太荒了
That looks ridiculous.
一切都能…透^科技…_成
Everything...is achievable...through technology.
托尼
Tony...
你太小，F在不懂
You're too young to understand this right now
所以我就先替你拍下@一段
so I thought I would put it on film for you.
@一切是槟愣打造
I built this for you.
有一天你明白…
And someday you'll realize that
@代表的不只是人的l明
it represents a whole lot more than just people's inventions.
它也是我生的成就
It represents my life's work.
@是未碇
This is key to the future.
我受到@r代科技的限制
I'm limited by the technology of my time.
但有一天你t解@一切
But one day you'll figure this out.
到r候你就改世界
And when you do...you will change the world.
我最ゴ蟮作…
What is and always will be my greatest creation...
永h就只有你
is you.
你好，先生
Hi, sir.
六美元
$6.
我]有X，我用@Q
I don't have any...
不行，@太多了   ]PS
No sir, that's too much.
不行啦，先生
No it's fine, take that.
快拿去吧
Take it, take it.
我不喜ge人拿|西o我
I don't like people hand me things so if you could
你把它放在那e
just drop that there that would be great.
你是Fb幔
Are you Iron Man?
有r候是
Sometimes.
我相信你！
We believe in you!
@算非法]收私人物
It was an illegal seizure of trademarked property.
波小姐？   放p
- Ms. Potts, Mr Stark is...- Here.
斯塔克先生…
He refuses to...
他不肯…   Γ]PS
I don't. It's fine.
我只要一下子
I'll just be a second.
斯塔克工I的立鍪恰
It's our position that Stark has
仍然碛旭R克二F盔甲的a
the means to maintain proprietary ownership of the Mark II platform.
斯塔克先生宣阉是Fb
When Mr. Stark announced he was the Iron Man
他向美承Z他保o我
he was making a promise to America.
他很@然K]有
Obviously he did not.
F在我lF他的秘
Now we learn that his secretary,
一叫小辣椒波的女生
a woman named Virginia "Pepper" Potts,
居然被任命樗顾克工I绦虚L
has been appointed CEO of Stark Industries executive.
她有什NYv？
What are her qualifications?
波小姐根本什NYv都…  不
Ms. Potts is doing nothing to manage the terrible situation...  No.
o音
Mute.
柏特…
Bert,
e跟我f我有最好的律
don't tell me that we have the best patent lawyers in the country
然後f你不我追V下去
and then not let me pursue this.
我把|西拿走…
I'll get this stuff out of here.
那就叫y署行政命令
Well then, tell the President to sign an order.
我在博[上再f
We'll talk about it at the expo.
h默明天要e行展示
Hammer's giving some presentation tomorrow evening.
托尼也去帷
Will Tony Stark be there?
我去幔
Will I?
不，他不去   我很想去
-No, he will not.- I'd like to be.
拜了
Bye.
有空幔   ]有
- Got a minute?- No.
你才v完，只要30秒
Come on, you just got off the phone.30 seconds.
29秒…28秒…
29 ... 28 ...
我_^淼r候…
I was driving over here, and I thought
想淼狼福但F在我不了
I was coming basically to apologize, but I'm not.
你不是淼狼傅模
You didn't come here to apologize?
不必f你也知道，我正在努力
That goes without saying, and I'm working on that.
但我K]有完全跟你f
But I haven't been entirely up front with you
我只想跟你和好
and I just wanna try to make good,
我能把@玩意移走幔
Can I move this?
@太扯了，就像摩天一
This is crazy I got ferris wheel...
我著想要…   不行
-I'm trying to get some... -No.
你知道人生有多短幔
Do you know how short life is?
我]有C表_…
And if I never got to express...
我也是最近才I悟到@一c
and by the way somewhat revelatory to me,
我不在乎…我是f我在乎…
I don't care... I mean, I care, it would be nice,
我K不期望你…
I'm not expecting you to...
好，我只想f，我要f…
Look, here's what I'm trying to say.
我先阻止你f下去
Let me just stop you right here, okay,
要是你再f一次“我”…
because if you say "I"
我就要拿|西砸你的^
one more time, I'm gonna actually hurl something at your head, I think.
我著I一家公司
I am trying to run a company.
你知道@有多y幔
Do you know have any idea what that entails?
知道
Yes.
大家都期待你Fb
People are relying on you to be Iron Man,
你s消失o
and you've disappeared.
我只能替你缁穑被e人痛
All I'm doing is putting out your fire and taking the heat for it.
我正在著做你做的事
I am trying to do the job that you were meant to do.
你Я瞬葺o我？
Did you bring me strawberries?
你知道全世界我只σ|西^敏幔
Did you know that there is only one thing on earth that I am allergic to?
草莓…
You're allergic to strawberries, uh-uh.
@是M步，小辣椒
This is progress, Pepper.
我就知道你和草莓有P
I knew there was correlation between you and this...
我需要你…
I need you...
我也需要你…
And I need you too, that's what I'm trying to say.
…R上x_
to leave now.
波小姐？
Ms Potts.
嗨，M
Hi, come on in.
25分後起w
Wheel's up in 25 minutes.
xx你
Thank you.
要什N幔老？
Anything else, boss?
]有了   我好…
- I'm good Hap.- I'll be just...
…我R上就
another minute.
我好像x了婚又失去小孩
I lost both the kids in the divorce.
]事，真的
That's...No.
你融入得好吧，妮坦莉？
Are you blending in well here, Natalie?
我是f融入斯塔克工I
Here at Stark... Enterprises.
你叫妮坦莉，Π桑
Your name is Natalie, isn't it?
我以槟z不合
I thought you two didn't get along.
K]有
No. That's not so.
你只是不P心我了
It's just me you don't care for.
完全]反？
No? Nothing?
你人都砹
Actually while you're here maybe
就可以和妮坦莉私人物件
you and Natalie could discuss the matter of personal belonging.
然了
Absolutely.
你就是不肯]嘴，是吧？
I'm surprised you could keep your mouth shut.
你真害，你真b
You're good. You are mind-blowingly duplicitous.
你是怎N做到的？
How do you do it?
你@三面g
You're a triple impostor.
我]^你@N人
I've never seen anything like it.
你有什N是真的幔
Is there anything real about you?
你真的f拉丁Z幔
Do you even speak Latin?
（拉丁Z）
Fallaces sunt rerum species.
什N意思？你f什N？
Which means?What did you just say?
意思是你可以自己回家
It means you can either drive yourself home
或是我派人押你回去
or I can have you collected.
你太害了！
You're good!
“未碇在@e”
卓S，你做出滴荒Ｐ
Jarvis, could you kindly backform a digital wireframe?
我需要一可操作投影面
I need a manipulable projection.
1974年斯塔克工I博[…
1974 Stark Expo
模型呙橥戤
model scanning complete, sir.
共有建B物？
How many buildings are there?
包括比利r松位幔
Am I to include the Belgian waffles stand?
我只是，秀o我看
It was rhetorical, just show me.
@看起硐袷颤N？
What does that look like to you, Jarvis?
有c像原子
Not unlike an atom.
原子核在@e
In which case, the nucleus... would be here.
把大地球x突@出
Highlight the Unisphere.
把走道拿掉，全都G掉
Notice the footpaths. Get rid of them.
你想_成什N？
What is it you're trying to achieve, sir?
我想lF…更正
I'm discovering,... correction, rediscovering...
我想重新lF一新元素
... a new element.
把景^弄掉，灌木病淠
Lose the landscape and the shrubbery there,trees,
停觥⒊隹凇⑷肟
parking lots, exits, entrances.
利用鐾ぷ榧
Structre protons and neutrons
成|子和中子
using flags the pavillions as the framework.
你死了20年要o我上n？
Dead for almost 20 years...still taking me to school.
你lF的新元素
The proposed element
能取代你在用的Z元素
should serve as a viable replacement for palladium.
x了，老爸
Thanks, Dad.
可惜的是，o法合成出
Unfortunately,it is impossible to synthesize.
溥M行大翻修
Get ready for major remodel, fellas!
是r候流些汗了
We're back in hardware mode.
f你x_^
How did you break the perimeter?
那是上子的事，你去哪e了？
That was like three years ago.Where have you been?
我有事
I was doing some stuff.
是幔课乙彩牵而且成功了
Yeah, well, me too and it worked.
我在和你合作
Hey, I'm playing for the home team, Colson
替你的男孩Fw做事
You and all your Fabulous Furry Freak Brothers.
你要我只钸是找我事？
Let me work, or break my balls?
@怎N在@e？
What's this doing here?
就是@
That's it.
拿o我
Bring it to me.
你知道@是什N？
You know what this is?
有用的|西
It's exactly what I need to make this work.
抬一下管道
Lift the coil.
快c，用力，很好
Go, go! Put your knees under it.There you go.
然後…
And...
放下去
- Drop it. - Okay.
完全平衡
Perfectly level.
我很忙，你想致铮
- I'm busy. What do you want?- Nothing.
f再，我被Good bye. I've been reassigned.
我要去新墨西哥州
Director Fury wants me in New Mexico.
迷人仙境
Fantastic, the land of enchantment.
大家都@Nf
So I'm told.
秘密任   差不多
- Secret stuff.- Something like that.
祝好\   拜
- Good luck.- Bye.
x了   我需要你
- Thanks.- We need you.
是啊，非常需要我
Yeah, more than you know.
K]有
Not that much.
永忡R加速器
Initializing prismatic accelerator.
接近最高能量
Approaching maximum power.
很温
That was easy.
恭喜了
Congratulations, sir.
你造了一新元素
You have created a new element.
反t接受更新後的核心
Sir, the reactor has accepted the modified core.
我_始M行y
I will begin running diagnostics.
嘿，伊凡
Hey, Ivan.
史丹hT跟我在一起
I got Senator Stern here.
我想他看看F士兵
Thought we'd swing over and look at some of the drone designs.
F士兵]浜
The drone is not going to be ready.
你是什N意思？
Not ready... What do you mean?
我只能展示，不能示
It can make presentation not demonstration.
那有什N不同？
What the hell is the difference?
展示，不能w，不能_火
Presentation, no fly, no shoot.
你能它做什N？
Wait. What can we make 'em do, I mean,
@是一鲕火秀耶
This is a weapons demonstration.
我能它敬Y
I can make salute.
敬Y？什N意思？
You can make salute, what do you mean make salute?
那是什N意思，伊凡？
What the hell does that mean, Ivan?
@不是我v好的l件
It's not what we agreed to, okay.
你答要做F盔甲
You promised me suits,
然後答要做F士兵
and then you promised me drones.
老兄，一切都OK的
Hey man, everything will be okay.
@不是我要的
This is not what I wanted.
他在@e，B人！
Hey, there he is, the bird man.
你_始喜g@只B了，Π桑
Oh, now you like the bird, is that right?
@是你的B幔课冶桓慊炝
Is that your bird?I'm confused.
你f不是，F在s成了好友
You said it wasn't, but now it's like you're best of pals.
你很勰侵圾B，Π桑
You love that bird, don't you?
把那只B拿走
You know what? Take the bird.
把他的枕^也拿走
Take his pillows too. Both of them.
有他的鞋子
And shoes, take his shoes.
我拿走你的|西，
I took your stuff.
感X怎樱亢懿凰幔
How does that make you feel?You feel bad?
很好
Good.
因槲乙埠懿凰！
Cause that's how I feel!
我了合s
We had a contract!
我救你一命，你o我F盔甲
I saved your life and you give me suits.
@是我的fh
That was our deal.
你s]有做到
And you did not deliver.
我不知道你是天才或_子
I don't know if you're a genius or a fraud.
我不知道你是什N
I don't know what you are!
幸好奶焐系粝乱Y物
Something really, really great fell into my lap.
不然你就把我害K了
If it hadn't, I'd be at your mercy tonight.
F在我碛懈牧及娴氖肥峡萍
Now I have a piece of Stark tech, and I pimped out myself.
你的F士兵只能丫暗谰
Now your overpriced paperweights are gonna look like a backdrop to my demonstration.
你懂我的意思幔
You dig what I'm gettin' at here?
也S你]搞清楚…
I don't know if you noticed,
我不f俄Z！
but I don't speak Russian!
我要去⒓硬┯[了
I'm gonna leave now. I'm gonna go to the expo.
搞不好能把到辣妹
Maybe I'll even get laid.
@些砘锸悄愕谋Ｄ
See these guys? They're your babysitters.
千fe惹毛他
They are not to be trifled with.
等我回碓僦匦抡合s的l件
When I get back, we're gonna renegotiate the terms of our agreement.
你一定要做到你答做的事
And you're gonna make good on our arrangements.
要是你做不到
Because if you don't, you're gonna be exactly what you were when I found you,
就跟以前一邮死人
a dead man.
懂幔
You got that?
也S你能在上看到我
Maybe you can watch me on TV.
老兄，把@e打咔Q
Dummy. You.Can we clean up this mess?
未@示a黼
Incoming call with a blocked number, sir.
我又可以接了，太好了
Phone privileges reinstated.Lovely.
考森，迷人仙境如何？
Colson, how's land of enchantment?
托尼，你好幔
Hey, Tony, how you doin'?
我加倍了D速
I doubled cycle.
什N？
You what?
你叫我加倍D速u造更多能量
You told me double cycle's more power.
很好的建h
Good advice.
你@死人^起砭神很好
You sound pretty spitely for a dead guy.
你也是
You too.
追黼
Trace it.
先生
Sir.
斯塔克的家族史⒈桓
Now the true history of Stark name will be written.
卓S，他在哪e？
Jarvis, where he is?
正在使用甲骨文W路
Accessing the Oracle grid.
美|岸
Eastern seaboard.
你爸在40年前ξ壹易遄龅氖
What your father did to my family over 40 years
我在40分δ阕鐾
I will do to you in 40 minutes.
起聿诲e，咱好好聊聊
Sounds good, let's get together and hash it out.
三州地^
Tri-state area.
曼哈D和近行政^
Manhattan and outlying boroughs.
希望你浜昧
I hope you're ready.
追失
Call trace incomplete.
“捍l和平”
先生！
Sir.
你就@舆M行y吧
You wanna run some tests, run 'em.
R上MbF盔甲
And assemble the suit while you're at it put it together now.
我不_定…
We are unclear as to the effects...
我不想！
I don't wanna hear it, Jarvis!
有椰子和金俚奈兜
It tastes like coconut...and metal.
哇，好耶！
Oh, wow, yeah!
我把停在@e
I'll keep the car down here, alright.
x了，霍根
Thank you Happy.
Z斯汀?h默的展示…
Justin Hammer, his presentation will
即⒃谥de行
begin shortly in the main pavilion.
好耶！
Yeah.
@硬β铮多x光R
That's what I'm talking about!Thanks for coming.
各位先生女士，L久以
Ladies and gentlemen,for far too long
我英勇的士兵冒U作
this country has had to place its brave men and women in harm's way.
後礓Fb出F了
But then the Iron Man arrived and we thought that
我以椴再有人拭
the days of losing lives were behind us.
但是他s不肯公_先M科技
Sadly that technology was kept out of reach.
@不公平，也不
That's not fair. That's not right.
而且太可惜了
And it's just too bad.
天啊
Oh, lord...
不^那仍是很棒的l明
Regardless it was an impressive innovation one that
成槭澜绺鞯氐念^l新
grabbed headlines the world over.
但今天各大笊绲穆┐罅
Today, my friends, the press is faced with quite a different problem.
他的油墨⒉蛴
They are about to run out of ink.
把@玩意移_
Get that out of here.
各位先生女士
Ladies and gentlemen...
今天我⑾虼蠹医榻B
...today I present to you
美方全新的面孔
...the new face of the United States military!
h默F士兵！
The Hammer drone!
F士兵！
Army!
海F士兵！
Navy!
空F士兵！
Air Force!
海痍F士兵！
Marines!
好耶！
Yeah!
它比啦啦T好太多了
That's a hell of a lot better than some cheerleaders, let me tell you.
m然@是革命性的科技
But as revolutionary as this technology is,
但是鋈匀恍枰真正的士兵
there will always be a need for a man to be present at the theater of war.
我很s幸能介B第一原型
Ladies and gentlemen, today I am proud to present to you the very first prototype
全面性威the variable threat response battle suit
空中校詹姆斯?_德
and its pilot Air Force Lt. Col. James Rhodes.
什N？
What?
h默工I向美和盟蟮健
For America and its allies,Hammer Industries, is reporting...
麻┐罅
We got trouble.
托尼，@e有平民
Tony, there are civilians present.
我是奉命行事，e在@e_打
I'm here on orders.Let's not do this right now.
向他]手
Give them a wave.
大家都有危U，我得救他
All these people are in danger.We gotta get them out of here.
F在你一定要信任我
You gotta trust me for the next five minutes.
我^，Y果在你家被打得很K
I tried that and I got tossed around your house, remember?
好，我J樗和f科合作
I think he's working with Vanko.
f科活著？
Vanko is alive?
他在哪e？
- Where is he?- What?
什N？   f科在哪e？
Where is Vanko?
l？   告V我
- Who?- Tell me.
你跑致铮老兄？
What are you doing here, man?
“瞄省
是你幔
Is that you?
不是我，不是我，我硬涣 我被i死了
No, I'm not doing that, it's not me.I can't move.I'm locked up, I'm locked up.
快走，整系y都被他控制了
Get out of here! Go!The whole system's been compromised!
我到外面再打吧
Let's take it outside.
“出印
不，不！
No!
卓S，我要控制他
Jarvis, break in, I need to own him.
遵命
Yes, sir.
托尼，我i定目肆
Tony, I'm locked on I have target locked.
目耸钦l？   你！
- On what?- On you.
托尼，我在你後面！
Tony on your six.
l生什N事？
What's going on, what's happening?
w被更改了
The software's been overwritten.
被更改是什N意思？
What?What do you mean it's been overwritten?
他控制了F士兵   不可能
- I think he slaved the drones.  - It is impossible.
打o警l
Call the guards
全都被切
All the phones are down, sir.
那就打o他的手C
Then call their cells.
手C也]有
Their cell phones are not working either, sir.
我被n在主C外面
He's locked us out of the mainframe.
@是l做的？
Who's locked you out of the mainframe?
走_，我可以搞定
Please, please, go away.I got this handled.
是幔   然了！
- Have you now?- Yes I do.
Fb不砭筒l生@N事
In fact, if your guy hadn't showed up
拜你走_，xx你
This wouldn't be happening Please now, go away!
我得把那臭婆娘弄走
Thank you.Listen we gotta get these bitches outta here.
告V我是l在搞鬼
You're gonna tell me who's behind this.
l在搞鬼？
Who's behind this?
伊凡，伊凡?f科
Ivan. Ivan Vanko.
他在哪e？
Where is he?
他在我的公司
He's at my facility.
臀医蛹~s警局部
- I need NYPD please.- No, no, no honey.
不！e打o警方！
Don't call the authorities!
_！o我_！
Step aside.
告V我你知道的一切
Tell me everything you know. Go.
卓S，情r如何？
How we doing Jarvis?
o法h端重新_C
Remote reboot unsuccessful.
l生什N事？
No one's answering the phone, what's going on?
上，我到h默工I
Get in the car. Take me to Hammer Industries.
我才不要送你到其他地方
I'm not taking you anywhere.
好吧，你要我_幔
Fine. You want me to drive?
不，我黹_，上
No, I'm driving. Get in the car
“失去B”
值煤茫小鬼
Nice work, kid.
多具F士兵在追你
You got multiples coming down on you.
我x博[愈h愈好
Let's get this away from the expo.
到了以後我要你守住外面
When we arrive I need you to watch the perimeter.
我要M去消缒
I'm gonna enter the facility and take down the target.
眼睛看前面！   知道了啦
- Watch the road.- I got it.
“失去B”
好，一群F士兵
Listen, listen, a pack has peeled off
它w回博[
and headed back to the expo.
收到
Got it.
我正逼近你！湎蚰汩_火！
I'm closing on you!It's coming in hot,
托尼，小心！
Tony! Watch it.
待在上
Stay in the car!
我才不要待在上
I'm not staying in the car.
我叫你待在上
I said stay in the car.
你穿的是什N？
What are you wearing?
我不能你一人M去
Look, I'm not letting you go in there alone.
你想兔Γe子熄火
You wanna help? Keep the car running.
好吧
Okay.
“外人侵入”
你不能M恚
Hey, you can't come in here!
“出印
每MF士兵用自己的Z言贤
Each set of drones is communicating in its own unique language.
挑一M，集中破解
Choose one and focus on that.
你怎N不俄Z？
Have you tried Russian? Why don't you try Russian.
搞定！
I got 'em!
小_，你在i定我幔
- Rhodey, you're still locked on? - Yeah.
穿好雨衣，我就要洗澡了
Drop your socks and grab your crocs, we're about to get wet on this ride.
等等…等等…
Wait, wait!
他x_了！
He's gone!
抱歉，我得p少橙盗
Sorry buddy, had to thin out the herd.
你在哪e？
What's your twenty?
你在致铮
What are you doing?
替_德的痿Yb重新_C
I'm rebooting Rhodey's suit.
托尼！
Tony!
“准SM入”
完成重新_C
Reboot complete.
救回你的好朋友了
You got your best friend back.
多x了，洛曼Z芙探T
Thank you very much, Agent Romanoff.
你的全新能量板很棒
Well done with the new chest-piece.
出的能量更
I'm reading significantly higher output
你的生命E象也很正常
and your vitals all look promising.
是啊，我r死不了，x了
Yes, for the moment I'm not dying. Thank you.
什N意思？你本砜焖懒耍
What do you mean you're not dying? Did you say you're dying?
是你幔
That you?
放心，我不死了
No, I'm not. Not anymore.
l生什N事？
What's going on?
我本硪告V你
I was going to tell you. I didn't want to..
你要告V我？你本硪死幔
You're gonna tell me you really were dying?
你]o我Cf
You didn't let me.
你槭颤N不告V我？
Why didn't you tell me that?
上次煎蛋缘r候本硪f
I was gonna make you an omelette and tell you!
你等度蜜月再聊吧
Hey, hey, save it for the honeymoon.
托尼，橙硪u
You got incoming, Tony.
看硭盯上你了
Looks like the fight's coming to you.
棒呆了，小辣椒？
Great. Pepper?
你F在]事了？
Are you okay now?
Γe生
I'm fine. Don't be mad. I will formally...
我很生
I am mad.
先等我W避^攻粼僬f
...apologize when I'm not fending off a Hammeroid attack!
我本硎窃谕尼斯的
We could've been in Venice.
噢，拜
Oh, please...
小_！
Rhodes!
快醒醒，我需要你
Snap out of it, buddy! I need you.
它攻砹耍快醒^
They're coming. Come on let's roll. Get up.
你可以把F盔甲拿回去
Oh man, you can have your suit back.
你]事吧？
Are you okay?
]事，x了
Yeah, thanks.
好，很抱歉
Tony, look... I'm sorry.
e道歉
Don't be.
我更信任你
No I should've trusted you more.
是我害你的，算了吧
I'm the one who put you in this position. Forget it.
Γ是你的e，我只想f抱歉
No it's your fault. I just wanted to say I'm sorry.
x了，我也只想你@Nf
Thank you. That's all I want to hear,
夥伴
partner.
它正在追恚有什NΣ撸
They're coming in hot. Any second. What's the play?
我要到制高c
Well we wanna take the high ground, okay.So let's take
把最猛的大炮У缴郊
the biggest gun up on that ridge.
收到，那你要去哪e？
- Got you.- Where do you wanna be?
你才要去哪e？
Where you going?
你在f什N？
What are you talking about?
我是f我啦
I mean me.
你是有一支大炮，但不是最猛的
I have a big gun, you are not the big gun.
e嫉妒我
Tony, don't be jealous.
很低No it's subtle with all the bells and whistles.
我@才叫狠角色   好吧
- It's called being a bad ass.- Fine.
你到制高c
Alright. You go up top.
我把它引
I'll draw 'em in.
e待在@e，太危U
But don't stay down here it's the worst place to be.
你有地方去，那我呢？
Okay you got a spot. Where's mine?
@e是⒙^
It's the kill box,
待在@e必死o疑
Tony, okay, this is where you go to die.
看到]？   有，好拥
- See that?- Yea, yea, nice.
小_…
Rhodey...
趴下恚
Get down!
下次你先用@招
Wow. I think you should lead with that next time.
抱歉，@招只能用一次
Yeah, sorry boss, I can only use it once. It's a one-off.
我5分前就跟你f了
I told you that five minutes ago.
你要抓的就是他
That's your guy here.
先生，你被捕了
- Excuse me? - Sir, you're placed under arrest.
你在_玩笑吧？   手放在背後
Hands behind your back, sir.
我想兔σ
I'm trying to help here.
我明白了，我知道你的
I get it. I see what you're doing.
你想把一切都w罪於我
Trying to pin this on me, huh?
好拥
That's good.
你_始像绦虚L一铀伎
You start to think like a CEO.
除κ
Taking out the competition.
我喜g
I like that.
你以槟阕我惹上大麻？
You think you're making a problem for me?
我才要你惹上大麻
I'm gonna make a problem for you.
我很快再面
I'm gonna be seeing you again, real soon.
他s硪葬
When they get here,
他守在|南和西方出口
I think you should station them at the Southeast and both West exits.
我P]了七地F
We shut down the seven train in and out of Willets Point already.
安排巴士d人到]P]的地F
Well, have city buses there to ferry people to operating lines.
好，你要一起幔
You coming with us?
不，我要等到大家都疏散了
No, I'm gonna stay until the park is clear.
好吧
ok
小心，一F士兵硪u
Heads up you got one more drone incoming.
@一看起聿惶一
This one looks different.
能量指堤e高
Repulsor signature is significantly higher.
回碚婧
Good to be back.
情r不妙
This ain't gonna be good.
我要用特e的武器Ω端
I got something special for this guy.
我用“前妻”把他打
I'm gonna bust his bunker with the ex-wife.
用什N？
The what?
h默的武器？
Hammer tech?
Α
Yeah.
我戆
We got this.
小_，我有c子
Rhodes! I got an idea.
你想英雄幔
You wanna be a hero?
什N？ 我需要一助手，
- What?- I can really use a sidekick.
e起手  @就是你的c子？
- Put your hand up.- This is your idea?
Yup.
我浜昧耍戆伞
I'm ready, I'm ready, go go go.
l射！
Hit him!
你了
You lose.
F士兵都自爆
All these drones are rigged to blow
我得s快W人
We gotta get out of here man.
小辣椒？
Pepper?
天啊，我受不了了
Oh my god, I can't take this anymore!
你受不了？   我受不了了
- You can't?- I can't take this.
看著我
What do you mean, look at me!
我的身w承受不了@N毫
My body literally cannot handle the stress.
我永h不知道你不死
I never know if you're gonna kill yourself...
或是Я苏家公司
or wreck the whole company...
我想我做得不e
I think I did okay!
老娘不至耍我要o
I quit.I'm resigning.
就是@
That's it.
你f什N？你不至耍
What did you just say?You're done?
@倒是很令人@
Surprising, I mean not surprising.
不…我t解
I get it.
你不必找藉口
You don't have to make any excuses.
我K]有找藉口
- I'm not making any excuses.- Well you actually were just making excuses.
你是真的在找藉口
I wasn't making an excuse but I'm actually very justified.
我]有找藉口，我是Φ
No, I wasn't making an excuse.I'm actually very justified
你得到更好的待遇
Listen. Hey, hey.You deserve better.
你一直把我照得好好的
You've taken such good care of me.
我每次有困y，你都救我
I've been in tough spot you got me through it, so.
xx你
Thank you.
xx你的t解
Thank you for understanding.
咱得怎N善後
Let's start clean up.
我理位D交的
I'll handle the transition. It'll be smooth.
怎N付媒w？
What about the press?
你才了一Y拜绦虚L
Because you only had the job for a week. That's gonna be...
感X像是了一百年
With you it's like dog years.
我知道
I know.
或像y…
I mean it's like the President.
好怪
Weird.
K不呀   不e，Π桑
No it's not weird. - It's okay, right?
Π  碓僖淮
- Yeah.- Run that by me again.
我X得好怪
I think it was weird.
你H得好像呻b在葡萄的海豹
You guys look like two seals fighting over a grape.
我o了…
I had just quit
你不必解，我全都了
- You don't have to do that.- I heard the whole thing.- You should get lost.
我先淼囊，去找自己的屋  你最好o我W人
I was here first.Get a roof.
我以槟]冷笑可f了
I thought you were out of one-liners?
那是最後一
That's the last one.
你才打得很猛
You kicked ass back there, by the way.
x了，你也是
Thank you. You too.
我的被炸了
Listen, my car got taken out in the explosions
我要先借用你的F盔甲
so I'm gonna have to hang on to your suit for a minute, okay?
不行，想都e想
Not okay with thats.
我不是在你
It wasn't a question.
我不接受…你要怎No？
I don't understand...
“超人盟初步蟾妗
我不想你看那份蟾
I don't think I want you looking at that.
我不_定@跟你有P
I'm not sure it pertains to you anymore.
至於@份蟾妗
Now this, on the other hand,
是洛曼Z芙探Tδ愕脑u估
is agent Romanoff's assessment of you.
你自己看吧
Read it.
性格分析
Personality overview:
斯塔克常做出n拥男
Mr Stark displays compulsive behaviour.
那只是上Y拜的事
In my own defense, that was last week.
有自我绲A向
Prone to self-destructive tendencies.
r我快死了耶
I was dying.
拜，我不都是@幔
I mean, please, aren't we all?
典型的…
Textbook...
自倏瘢
narcissism?
我同意
Agreed.
x到@e…
Okay, here it is.
超人盟招募u估
Recruitment assessment for Avenger Initiative,
Fb…可以
Iron Man, yes.
我得考]看看
I gotta think about it.
^mx下去
Read on.
托尼?斯塔克…不被推]？
Tony Stark not recommended?
@]有道理
That doesn't make any sense.
你怎N能接受另一我
How can you approve me
s不接受真正的我？
but not approve me?
我有全新的心K
I got a new ticker,
也打算好好Υ小辣椒
I'm trying to do right by Pepper.
我的PS很定
I'm in a stable-ish relationship.
所以你目前只能任
Which leads us to believe at this juncture we'd only like to use you as a consultant.
你不起我
You can't afford me.
不^我意用我的s聘M…
Then again I will waive my customary retainer
你臀乙小忙
in exchange for a small favor.
A府要Co我和小_
Rhodey and I are being honored in Washington
我需要一位元CFe
and we need a presenter.
我想想k法
I'll see what I can do.
今天我很s幸淼竭@e
It is my honor to be here today
Co詹姆斯?_德中校
to present these distinguished awards to Lt. Col. James Rhodes
以及托尼?斯塔克先生
and Mr. Tony Stark who is of course
毋庸置疑，他是
a national treasure.
中校，感x你的表F
Thank you Lieutenant Colonel for such an exceptionally distinguished performance.
@是你得的
You deserve this.
xx
Thank you, sir.
斯塔克先生
Mr Stark,
感x你@N秀的表F
thank you for such an exceptionally distinguished performance.
@是你得的
You deserve this.
抱歉
Oh sorry.
pp一刺很惹人，Π桑
Funny how annoying a little prick can be, isn't it?
咱砗险瞻
Let's get a photo.
<i>之後有[藏情，先e走_</i>
新墨西哥州迷人仙境
L官…我找到了
Sir, we've found it.